[ Music ]
[音乐]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning and welcome to
&gt;&gt; 上午好 欢迎
Data Flow Through SwiftUI.
大家来到 SwiftUI 中的数据流
My name is Luca Bernardi and I
我叫 Luca Bernardi
will later be joined by my
稍后会有一位我的朋友 也是我的同事
friend and colleague, Raj
Raj Ramamaurthy
Ramamaurthy.
加入讲演
Are you guys excited about
大家对 SwiftUI 感到兴奋吗
&gt;&gt; [Simultaneously] Yeah.
&gt;&gt; [齐声回答] 兴奋
&gt;&gt; Sweet. I'm super excited to
&gt;&gt; 很好 今天来到这儿
be here today.
我感到非常高兴
SwiftUI is the shortest path to
SwiftUI 是制作一个优秀 App 的
a great app, but we also
最便捷的途径
designed it from the ground up
但是我们也从头开始设计
with the goal of solving the
目标是降低
complexity of UI development.
UI 开发的复杂程度
That means that data is a first
这就意味着数据在 SwiftUI 中
class citizen in SwiftUI.
是第一类对象
In this talk, we are going to
在这次讲演中
show you the simple but powerful
我们将向大家展示一个
tool that you have at your
简单却有用的工具
disposal to flow data through
你可以用它
your view hierarchy.
使数据在视图层级中流动
This tool can help you achieve app that
这个工具可以帮助你
are not only beautiful but also
设计美观且好用的 App
We will also look under the hood
我们也将会深入内部机制
of how SwiftUI updates your view
看看 SwiftUI 如何更新视图层级
hierarchy to guarantee that you
来确保
always have a correct and
你可以正确而又持续地
consistent representation of
呈现你的数据
And finally, we will empower you
最后我们将为你
with a mental framework for
在脑海中建立一个框架
understanding your data and the
去理解你的数据
tool available to you.
和可用工具
But before moving on, what do we
在继续说明之前 我们必须要问
mean by data?
数据是什么意思
Data is all the information that
数据是所有
drives your UI.
驱动你 UI 的信息
Data comes in all sort of shapes
数据的形态结构多种多样
One example is stating your UI
一个例子是
like the state of a toggle.
像 Toggle 中的状态一样
Data also represent model data,
数据还代表模型数据
such as the object that drives a
比如驱动一列信息的对象
We have a number of tool at your
我们有许多工具
disposal depending on what you
供你选择
want to achieve.
取决于你想做什么
You've probably seen some of
你也许已经在之前的讲解中
this tool in previous talk.
看到了这些工具
But if you are not familiar with
如果你对它们并不熟悉
them, don't worry we're going to
不必担心
explain what they are and when
我们会解释它们是什么
to use them.
以及什么时候用得到
At the end of this talk, you'll
听完讲解后
know exactly what tool to use
你就会清楚地知道使用哪个工具
and when.
以及什么时候使用
But before showing you this
但是在展示工具之前
tool, I would like to illustrate
我想先阐释
the two guiding principle that
两个指导性原则
inspired us in designing them.
这两个原则启发了我们的设计
The first principle is that
第一个原则是
every time you read a piece of
每次你在视图中
data in your view, you're
读取数据时
creating a dependency for that
你都在为那个视图创建一个依赖
This is a dependency because
这是一个依赖
every time the data changes,
因为每当数据发生变化
your view has to change to
你的视图也要变化
reflect the new value.
去反映一个新的值
For example, here in blue I have
举个例子
a view showing some playback
这里蓝色的是播放控制的视图
control and the view needs to
这个视图需要
read some data in purple.
读取紫色的数据
Every time this value changes,
每当这个值变化时
we need to update the view.
我们都要更新视图
And so additionally, defining
所以 定义这个依赖
process and it can quickly
是个手动的过程
become a complex endeavor.
很快就会变得复杂起来
But just like viewing SwiftUI
正如查看 SwiftUI
are declarative, data dependency
数据依赖
are as well.
也是声明式的
There is no manual
并不是手动
synchronization or invalidation.
同步或失效
With SwiftUI, you simply
通过 SwiftUI
describe the dependency to the
你只需用很少的工具
framework using few tools and
把依赖描述给框架
the frameworks handles all the
框架就会处理剩下的
rest.
这就意味着你可以
focus on building the best
将你的注意力集中在
experience for your user.
为用户提供最佳体验上
The second principle is that
第二条原则是
every piece of data that you're
在视图层级中
reading in your view hierarchy
你读取的每一条数据
has a source of truth.
都有一个数据源
The source of truth can live in
数据源存在
your view hierarchy.
在视图层级里
For example when you have some
比如说你有状态
state about something should be
要折叠
collapsed or not, or it can be
或者不折叠
external such as when you're
它也可以是外部的
displaying a message coming from
比如当你显示一个
a persistent model.
来自不变模型的信息时
Regardless of where the source
不论数据源在哪里
of truth live, you should always
你应该一直有一个
have a single source of truth.
单一数据源
Duplicated source of truth can
重复数据源会
lead to bug and inconsistency
会产生 Bug 和不一致
because you always have to be
你要一直很小心
careful in keeping them in sync.
让它们保持同步
Think about all the time you've
想一想你一直重复
duplicated the same piece of
同一条数据
data, for example, into sibling
比如在同级视图里重复同一条数据
view and how all the complexity
想一想消息传递
of posting notification,
是多么复杂
KV observing or
KV 观察
responding to a different
或响应一个不同的
sequence of event has caused
事件顺序
your bug.
会产生 Bug
And it's pretty easy to get
很容易就出错了
And they've made the same
它们会重复同一个错误
mistake many time.
很多次
What you shall do instead is
反而 你需要做的是
lift up the data into a common
把数据提取到一个
ancestor and let the two
共同的父级节点
children have a reference to it.
让两个子节点链接到父节点
When you have a single source of
当你有一个单一数据源时
truth, you're eliminating
你就消除了这种
inconsistency bug between view
视图和数据
and your data.
不一致的 Bug
And you can use the tool
你就可以用
available in the language to
语言有的工具
enforcing variant in your data.
在你的数据中执行变量
With this principle in mind,
记住这个原则
take a step back, look at all
退一步 看看
the source of truth in your
你代码里的所有数据源
code, and then use this
用这个原则
information to make decision
去决定
about the structure of your
数据的结构
data.
在我来 Apple 总部
good podcast during my commute
上班的路上
to Apple Park.
我特别喜欢听一个很棒的播客
And I thought it will be great
我觉得用 SwiftUI
to build a podcast player with
做一个播放器是个好主意
SwiftUI.
在这次讲解中
throughout the talk to
我会用这个做例子
demonstrate all the tool
展示所有的
available to you.
可用工具
Here is the UI that we are going
这是我们将要建构的 UI
It's the interface for the
这是播放器的界面
player when we're going to
我们需要它显示
display the show and episode
节目和剧集的名字
title, the playback button, and
播放按钮
the current time.
和当前时间
We are going to build this UI
我们将一步一步
step by step.
建构这个 UI
But let's start by creating a
首先创建一个视图
view that show the current
显示当前剧集的视图
We can start by creating a new
第一步是创建一个新视图
view, Playerview, and this view
PlayerView
has one property.
这个视图有一个属性
That stored the current playing
存储着当前播放剧集
And we want to display the
我们还想要显示
episode show and title.
剧集和标题
So in the body, we'll make a
所以在主体中
VStack containing two texts so
我们会做一个 VStack 包含两个文本
that they're stacked vertically.
这样它们会纵向排列
And regular Swift property are
基本的 Swift 属性
your first tool.
是你的第一个工具
They're great when you have a
当你有一个视图
view that needs to read all the
需要读取所有的派生数据访问时
access to a derived piece of
它是很好用的
This is data that will be
这条数据会被它的父节点
provided to the view by its
提供给视图
But now, I want to be able to
现在我想让它有
play and pause, so let's have
播放和暂停的功能
We had a new property indicating
我们有一个新的属性
whether the episode is playing
表明当前剧集是否在播放
or not.
现在 显示不同片段的图像
different clip depending on the
取决于
value of isPlaying.
isPlaying 这个值
But now I want to make the Play
但是现在我想让播放键
button interactive so that when
有交互功能
the user taps on it, would
用户按播放键时
toggle the Playback state and
播放状态会切换
change the image as well.
图片也会随之改变
And we can do that by using a
我们可以用 Button （按钮）
button.
Button 包含一些内容
an action to execute when the
运行一个动作
user taps on it.
当用户点击这个它时
In the action, we just toggle
我们只是切换
isPlaying.
isPlaying
But if we go to build a run, we
但如果我们运行一下
get a compiler error.
就会出现编译错误
But this is good because it's
这是个好事情
keeping us on the right path and
通过 UI 的
through to one of the general
其中一条普遍原则
principles of UI.
把我们引上正确的道路
We don't mutate the view
我们不改写视图层级
Every time your UI is updated,
你的 UI 每次更新
it's because some view body is
都是因为某个视图主体
generating a different value.
在生成新的值
And in order to handle case like
为了处理这种情况
this, we have a tool that's
我们有一个工具
called State.
叫作 State （状态）
So let's have home state through
我们在这个视图里创建一个主状态
We can do that by using the
通过 isPlaying 属性上的
state property wrapper on the
State Property Wrapper
isPlaying property.
我们可以实现这一点
And by doing this, we are
这么做相当于
telling the system that
告诉系统
isPlaying is a value that can
isPlaying 是个值
change over time and that the
它可以变化
PlayerView depends on it.
播放器视图会随它变化
Now if we build a run, we won't
现在再运行一下
get a compiler error.
就不会出现编辑错误了
And when the user taps on the
用户每轻点一次按钮
button, the state value changes
状态值都会变化
and the framework will generate
框架就会为这个视图
a new body for this view.
生成一个新主体
If you're not familiar with
如果你不了解
Property Wrapper, it's a
Property Wrapper
powerful new feature in Swift
它是 Swift 5.1 里非常有用的一点
But we're not going into much
至于它们是如何运作的
detail about how they work.
我们不再细说
And if you want to learn more,
如果你想了解更多的话
check out these two great
可以去看这两个很好的分会议
For this talk, all you need to
在今天这个讲演中
know is that when you add the
你只需要知道
Property Wrapper, you're
当你添加 Property Wrapper 时
wrapping this property and
你就是在打包这个属性
augment it with some additional
并当它读写时
behavior when it's read or
为它增加一些额外操作
And you might wonder, how does
你可能想知道
this work?
这是怎么实现的
What is this additional behavior
这个额外操作
with state?
是什么
When you state the framework,
当你声明框架
allocate the persistent storage
为视图上的变量
for the variable on the view we
分配永久存储时
have and track it as a
我们会追踪它为一个依赖
dependency because if the system
因为如果系统给你
is creating storage for you, you
创建了一个存储
always have to specify an
你必须总是明确规定
initial constant value.
一个初始常量值
View can be recreated often by
视图经常会被系统重建
the system, but with state, the
但是对于 State 来说
framework knows that it needs to
尽管视图同样有很多次更新
persist the storage across
框架知道它需要
multiple update of the same
永久存储
And it's a good practice to
这是个很好的操作
explicitly mark state property
清楚地声明状态属性
as private to really enforce the
是私有变量
idea that state is owned and
真正实现
managed by that view
状态由视图所有和管理
But I want to take you behind
但是我想深入内部结构
the scene and show you what's
让你们看看
happening when the user is
当用户点击按钮时
tapping on the button.
会发生什么
Let's start with view hierarchy
从我们刚才展示的
we just showed.
视图层级开始
We just say that when-- that
我们刚才说
when we define some state, the
当我们定义了一个状态时
framework is allocating
框架会为你
persistent storage for you.
分配永久存储
One was the special property of
状态变量的一个特殊属性是
state variable is that SwiftUI
当它们变化时
kind of start when they change.
SwiftUI 就开始了
And because SwiftUI knows that
因为 SwiftUI 知道
the state variable was writing
状态变量正在写主体
the body, it knows that the view
它知道视图渲染
rendering depend on that state
取决于状态变量
When the user interact with the
当用户和按钮互动时
button, the framework execute
框架就会运行动作
its action which in turn will
这个动作继而
meet at some state.
会和某个状态关联
The runtime the data-- the state
运行时数据
does change and starting
状态确实会变化
validating their view that owns
并验证状态的视图
the state, which mean it will
这也就是说
recompute the body of that view
它会重新计算那个视图的主体
and all of its children.
以及它所有的子类
In this sense, all the changes
在这种意义上
always flow down through your
所有的变化都会一直
view hierarchy.
贯穿你的视图层级
And we're able to do these very
这样效率很高
efficiently because the
这是因为
framework is comparing the view
框架会比较视图
and rendering again only what is
而且只会重新渲染改变了的地方
This is exactly what we
这正是我们
mentioned earlier when we say
之前提到的
that the framework manages the
框架可以
dependency for you.
为你管理依赖
But we also talk about source of
我们刚才还提到数据源
truth before and you should
要记住
remember that every time you
每次你
declare a state, you define a
声明一个状态
new source of truth that is
你就定义了一个数据源
owned by your view.
这个数据源是属于视图的
And while this is so important
这点很重要
that I'm showing to you in big
我用了更大的字母来强调
letter, another important
另一个重要的点是
takeaway is that view are a
视图是状态的
function of state, not a
一个函数
sequence of event.
而非事件顺序
Traditionally, you respond to
传统方法是
some event by directly mutating
通过直接修改视图层级
your view hierarchy.
响应某个事件
For example, by adding or
比如 通过添加或者删除
removing a subview or changing
一个 subview
the alpha.
或改变 alpha
Instead, in SwiftUI, you mutate
但是在 SwiftUI 里
some state and the state work as
你修改某个状态
a source of truth from which you
这个状态就是数据源的函数
derive your view.
通过这个就可以生成视图
This is where SwiftUI,
这就是 SwiftUI
declarative syntax shine.
声明式语法出色的地方
You describe your view given the
你鉴于当前状态
current state.
描述视图
And this is also how SwiftUI
SwiftUI 就是这样
helps you manage the complexity
降低了 UI 开发的复杂程度
of UI development allowing you
让你可以写一个
to write beautiful and correct
好看又准确的交互界面
You can think of your app as a
你可以把 App 看作
constant feedback loop between
一个用户和设备之间的
your user and the device.
持续反馈循环
It all start with your user.
一切都从用户开始
The user interact with your app
用户和 App 交互
generating an action.
生成一个动作
The action is executed by the
动作被框架执行
framework and mutate some state.
修改某个状态
The system detect that the state
系统发现状态发生了变化
has changed and so it knows that
所以它就知道
it needs to update the view that
它需要根据状态
depends on the state.
刷新视图
This update will produce a new
这个刷新给了 UI
version of your UI that your
一个新的形式
user can interact with.
用户继续和新形式互动
This model where data always
在这个模型中
flow in a single direction,
数据流向是单一向的
instead is your single final
它是所有变化的
point for all the changes, make
单一终点
the view update predictable and
让视图刷新变得
simple to understand.
可预测且易理解
And now that we understand
现在我们弄明白了状态
state, I want to go back to the
我想回到 AppWare 构建
AppWare building and make some
并做一些优化
So the first thing I want to
我想做的第一件事是
change is that whenever the user
每次用户按下
taps on Pause, the episode title
暂停键 剧集名
should change to gray.
都会变成灰色
And we already know how to do
我们已经知道怎么做了
We can just use our isPlaying
我们只需要用 isPlaying 状态
state and choose the right text
选择正确的文字颜色
Next, I love some good
接下来我想做一些重构
And if you have seen the SwiftUI
如果你已经看过 SwiftUI 的
essential tool, you already know
你就已经知道
that view are a locust
视图在 SwiftUI 里
obstruction in SwiftUI.
是一个 Locust 阻塞
You shall not be afraid of
不必害怕
grouping meaningful piece of
将视图中有意义的数据
data in your view into smaller
合并为可以被一起编写的
and reusable component that can
更小的
be composed together.
可重复使用的组件
And that's a good candidate
正好可以以此为例
That's a code for the Play and
这是播放按钮和暂停按钮
Pause button.
的代码
So let's encapsulate this logic
封装这个逻辑
into its own view.
到它自己的视图
And we can call this PlayButton.
命名为 PlayButton
And now let's take a look at
现在看一下
implementation of PlayButton.
PlayButton 的实现
This is the same code as before
代码还是一样的
just encapsulated into a new
只是封装到了一个新视图
But notice that we made the new
但是注意这里我们做了一个新状态
state here but state is not the
但是状态不是正确的工具
By using state, we've created
使用状态
another source of truth for
我们就为 isPlaying 建立了一个新数据源
isPlaying, which we have to keep
这样我们必须
in sync with the state in the
和父级 PlayerView 的状态
parent PlayerView.
保持同步
And that's not what we want.
这不是我们想要的效果
What we want is to make this a
我们想做的是
reusable component.
让它成为可重复使用的组件
So this view shall not own a
所以这个视图不会拥有
source of truth, it just need to
一个数据源
be able to read a value and
它只能读取一个值
mutate it.
然后改写它
But it doesn't need to own
但是它不需要拥有状态
state.
我们有处理这种情况的工具
It's called binding.
这个工具叫作 Binding（绑定）
By using the Binding Property
通过 Binding Property Wrapper
Wrapper, you define an explicit
给数据源
dependency to a source of truth
定义一个清楚的依赖
without owning it.
而不拥有它
Additionally, you don't need to
而且 你不需要
provide an initial value because
提供初始值
the binding can be derived from
因为绑定可以从状态中生成
So let's see how does-- how this
看一下效果如何
fits in our example.
是不是很适合我们的例子
So the only change that we need
我们唯一要做的就是
to make is to use the binding
用 Binding Property Wrapper
property wrapper and omit the
删除初始值
It's that simple.
就是这么简单
Let's now see how we can provide
现在来看一下
a binding into PlayButton by
如何通过返回 PlayerView
going back to our PlayerView.
为 PlayButton 提供一个绑定
PlayerView is still holding the
PlayerView 依旧持有状态
That's your source of truth.
这是你的数据源
From the state, you can derive a
在属性名字上
binding by using the dollar
使用美元符号
prefix on the property name.
你就可以从状态生成一个绑定
This is your way to allow a
这是你让组件
component to access your state
通过绑定访问状态的方法
The dollar prefix is another
美元符号是 Property Wrapper 的
feature of property wrapper.
另一个特色
And if you want to learn more,
如果你想了解更多
please watch the modern Swift
请看现代 Swift API 设计讲演
I want for you to pause for a
我想我们可以暂停一秒
second and appreciate how simple
欣赏一下这是多么
but powerful this is.
简单却有效
PlayButton does not contain a
PlayButton 不包含
copy of the isPlaying value.
isPlaying 值的主体
Just as a reference to it
只是通过绑定
through the binding, so there is
作为它的引用
no need to keep this data in
所以没有必要
sync between your view.
让数据和视图保持同步
And I want to contrast this with
我想把这个
what we have to write today in
和我们现在使用的 UIKit GraphKit
UI kit, graph kit.
对比一下
You have a view controller that
我们有一个 View Controller
owns multiple view that need to
有多个视图
respond to user interaction by
需要响应我们用户的交互
manually setting up target
要非常麻烦地设定目标 动作
action or defining a delegate.
或者定义委托
You have to observe the model
你需要观察模型变化
change and respond to those
并且也要响应事件
Every time any value changes,
每次有值变化时
you have to read the value and
你都需要读取值
set it everywhere it's needed.
把它设置在任何需要它的地方
As soon as the complexity of
一旦你的 App 复杂起来
your app grows welling up with a
这就成了大问题
massive problem and I'm sure all
我确信
of you know what I'm talking
在座诸位都知道
about here.
我说的这种情况
The whole purpose of
View Controller 的整体目标
ViewController is to keep your
就是让你的数据
data in sync with your view.
和你的视图保持同步
This is all complexity that I--
这是你我要处理的复杂难题
you have to manage, but not in
但是在 SwiftUI 中不存在
You have a simple tool to define
你有一个简单的工具
your data dependency and the
来定义数据依赖
framework takes care of all the
框架会处理其他的
And well, you don't need a
你再也不需要
ViewController anymore.
View Controller 了
[ Applause and Cheering ]
[掌声 欢呼]
This idea is so powerful.
这个想法非常有用
This is applied throughout our
这应用在整个框架中
If you take a look at the API
如果你看一下组件的 API
for component like Toggle,
如 Toggle
TextField and Slider, they all
TextField 和 Slider
expect a binding.
它们都需要一个绑定框架
The framework keeps you in
让你控制
control of where the source of
数据源在的地方
You create the data and give
你创建数据
that to the component, a
把它给组件
reference to it without ever
只是作为一个引用
duplicating that information or
而不需要重复信息
manually keep that in sync.
或者费力保持同步
And that's pretty amazing.
这真是太棒了
In SwiftUI views are so many app
在 SwiftUI 视图中
that can views for layout,
有很多 App 可以查看
navigation, and much more.
布局 导航等
And in fact they are your single
实际上它们是你的
composition primitive.
单一原生组件
They're also a great tool for
它们也是好工具
encapsulating presentation logic
用来为单一数据
for a single piece of data.
封装表示逻辑
The frameworks allows you and
框架使你能够
encourage you to create small
并鼓励你创建小的视图
view to represent a single piece
去呈现一条
of data that can be composed
可以被一起编写的
And this is, again, the
单个数据
framework guiding you to our
再一次 框架带领你
composition of small unit that
编写小单元
you can reason about.
让你更清楚明白
So let's go back to our example
现在回到我们的例子
I've shown this UI to my
我把这个 UI 给我的设计师看了
designer and she's very
她非常惊讶
impressed by how little code I
没想到这么少的代码
had to write.
就能有这些效果
But she suggested some
她也提出了一些优化的建议
We should animate the transition
我们应该把播放和暂停的
within Play and Pause.
过渡变化动画化
Fortunately, it's very easy for
幸运的是
me to make my designer because
这很简单
the framework keeps track of
因为框架追踪了
everything that has changed.
所有变化了的东西
It's incredibly easy and
难以置信
powerful to drive an animation
用状态驱动动画
with state.
是多么简单强大
By wrapping the mutation to the
用一个动画模块
binding with an animation block,
通过打包改写给绑定
the framework will animate the
当值改变时
transition when the value
框架会动画这个过渡变化
And you will always get the
直到最后的状态
correct animation to the final
你都会一直得到正确的动画
If you want to learn more about
如果你想了解更多
SwiftUI powerful animation and
关于 SwiftUI 强大的动画和布局系统
layout system and how to make
以及如何制作优秀 App 的信息
amazing app, I invite you to
我建议大家看一下
watch Building Custom View in
在 SwiftUI 中构建自定义视图这个分会
We've now seen state and
现在我们已经了解了 State 和 Binding
binding, but SwiftUI has quite
但是 SwiftUI 还有一些绝活
few more trick up its sleeve.
大家没有看到
And to show you more, I want to
为了让大家了解得更多
invite Raj on stage.
我现在要请 Raj 上台
Raj?
Raj
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Luca.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Luca
I'm going to walk you through a
接下来我会介绍
few of the other tools we have
一些其他工具
from managing data in SwiftUI.
在 SwiftUI 中它们可以用来管理数据
And by the end of this session,
听了这个讲演
you'll be able to design and
你就可以设计和构建
build robust reusable components
稳固的可重复使用的组件
that operate on all kinds of
可以应用在各种数据上
data.
大家刚才也看到了
number of powerful tools for
我们有很多有用的工具
managing data in SwiftUI.
可以在 SwiftUI 中处理数据
And Luca already covered a few
Luca 已经介绍了一些
of them such as using state,
比如使用 State
binding, or even just using a
Binding
Swift property.
甚至只用 Swift Property
I'm going to take you through
我会介绍
the rest of these exciting tools
剩下的工具
starting with external changes
以 SwiftUI 中的外部变化
in SwiftUI.
作为开始
So I want to bring back the
我们现在回到
diagram that Luca just showed
Luca 刚才为大家展示的图解
And in this diagram, the user
在这个图解中
interacted with the application.
用户和 App 互动
This created an action which
这形成了一个动作
resulted in a mutation to some
结果是改写了状态
state and that was driven into a
这就生成了
new copy of the view that was
视图的新主体
rendered to the user.
提供给用户
Well, some events are initiated
一些事件从外部被初始化
externally such as a timer or
比如计时器和通知
But remember, in SwiftUI, your
但是记住 在 SwiftUI 中
views are a function of some
你的视图是状态的函数
There's a single funnel point
所有的改变
for all of your changes.
只有一个单一漏斗点
And what this means is that
这意味着
SwiftUI reacts to these external
SwiftUI
changes the same way it does to
用响应用户操作的方法
user interaction.
响应外部更改
So when a timer fires or a
所以当计时器启动
notification is received, the
或者接收到通知时
process looks pretty much the
过程看起来是差不多的
We create an action, perform a
我们创建了一个动作
mutation on some state, we get a
执行一些状态改写
new copy of the view and that's
生成视图的新副本
rerendered to the user.
重新提供给用户
And in SwiftUI, we have a single
在 SwiftUI 中
abstraction for representing
为表述这些外部事件
these external events.
我们有单一抽象化
And it's called a Publisher.
它被成为 Publisher
The publisher comes from the new
Publisher 来自一个新的
combined framework.
组合框架
Combine is a unified declarative
Combine 是一个统一声明式 API
API for processing values over
随时间处理数据
Now, we're not going to go into
今天我们
the details of Combine today,
不会细说 Combine
but you should definitely check
但是大家一定要去看
out these related sessions where
一些相关的讲解
you can find out much more.
这样可以了解更多
For our purpose, there is one
要达到我们的目的
thing to remember when using
需记住一点
these publishers with SwiftUI,
在 SwiftUI 里用 Publisher 时
they should omit on the main
它们应该删除主线程
Combine provides an easy to use
Combine 提供了一种用操作符的简单方法
operator called Receive On for
被称为 Receive On
For more information, you can
想知道更多的话
check out the Combine and
可以去看
Practice session.
Combine and Practice 分会
OK. Let's walk through this with
现在我们通过例子来看一下
an example.
它是如何运行的
Now, our users can sometimes get
有时候用户
lost listening to podcasts and
不知道自己听播客听到了哪儿
they can get tired of hearing
他们厌倦听年轻的一代
about the same millennial ramble
接连好几个小时
on about avocado toast for hours
大谈特谈牛油果吐司
So, we're going to add a time
所以我们要为播客播放器
stamp to our podcast player so
加一个时间戳
they know exactly where they are
这样用户就知道
in the episode.
自己听到了哪儿
To do that, we'll add some state
要实现这个效果
representing the current time
我们要加 State 表现当前时间
and a text that draws that
和描绘该值的文本
value.
接下来我们会使用 onReceive 修饰符
Conveniently, I already built a
很方便 我已经构建了一个 publisher
publisher that fires when the
当前时间一改变
current time changes.
它就会启动
And I'll use that publisher by
我会使用那个 publisher
passing it into this onReceive
传递给 onReceive 修饰符
Additionally, I'll also provide
另外 我还会给一个闭包
a closure that will execute when
当 publisher 删除时
the publisher omits.
这个闭包会运行
And that's it.
就是这样
In doing this, we've described a
这么做 我们已经给 SwiftUI
dependency to SwiftUI.
描述了依赖
So now, when the currentTime
现在当 currentTime 刷新时
updates, we'll update our state
我们会刷新状态
and SwiftUI knows that there's a
SwiftUI 就会知道
dependency there.
那儿有一个依赖
So we'll update the label
标签就会自动刷新
There's no manual invalidation
就无需费力
or management here.
去做失效或管理了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So we briefly covered external
我们已经简单说明了
changes in SwiftUI.
SwiftUI 里的外部变化
Next, I want to talk to you
接下来我会介绍
about external data.
外部数据
For that, we have the
对于外部数据
BindableObject Protocol.
我们有 BindableObject 协议
BindableObject is a convenient
BindableObject 是
way to use the well encapsulated
使用封装了的 测试过的
tried and true model that you
你已有的“true”模型的
already have.
简便方法
It's great for teaching SwiftUI
这对教 SwiftUI
about the reference type model
你已经架构的引用类型模型
you've already built.
是非常有用的
This is data that you own and
这是你拥有并需要管理的数据
SwiftUI just needs to know how
SwiftUI 只需要知道
to react to changes in that
如何在这个数据中响应改变
data.
我们换个例子
Our users expect that their
用户希望
podcasts sync across all of
播客可以在他们
their devices and I've been
所有的设备上同步
tasked with adding this
我负责添加这个功能
So I've already gotten started
所以我已经开始了
and I've built up a model and
我已经建立了一个模型
now it's time to use the model
现在是时候使用
that I've built in our view
我在视图层级里做好的模型
hierarchy and bring it into our
把它带到
podcast player.
我们的播客播放器
Let me show you how easy that
看看多么简单
You could see here a sketch of
这里是我们搭建的
the model that we built.
模型的一个草图
All I need to do to use this
要通过 SwiftUI 用这个模型
model with SwiftUI is to conform
我要做的只是
it to the BindableObject
确认它到 BindableObject 协议
With BindableObject, all we need
用 BindableObject
to provide is a publisher.
我们需要提供的只是一个 publisher
This publisher represents
这个 publisher 显示
changes to our data.
对数据的更改
And remember, the combined
记住组合 publisher
publisher is our single
是我们为表现
abstraction for representing
对 SwiftUI 外部更改的
external changes to SwiftUI.
单一抽象化
So here, we'll provide a
这里 我们会在 didChange property
publisher in the didChange
提供一个 publisher
PassthroughSubject is a
PassthroughSubject 是一个 publisher
And then SwiftUI will subscribe
接着 SwiftUI 会订阅这个 publisher
to this publisher, so it knows
所以它知道什么时候
when to update our view
更新我们的视图层级
Then in the advanced method,
在高级操作中
when we mutate our model, we'll
当我们改写模型时
simply call send on the
我们只是简单地发送 publisher 请求
Now, note that for correctness,
现在 注意 为保证正确
we need to do this any time our
不管什么时候 模型一变化
model changes so that our view
我们就需要这样做
hierarchy can stay up to date.
这样视图层级才能保持刷新
But thankfully, SwiftUI has our
幸好 SwiftUI 可以帮助我们
It handles these updates
它优雅地应对这些数据
gracefully, so you get great
帮我们很好且正确地
performance and correctness.
实现这个效果
So now we've built our model and
现在我们已经搭建了模型
its conformance to the
以及它对 BindableObject 协议的确认
Next, I want to show you how to
接下来我将向大家展示
use that model in the view
如何在视图层级中用模型
Remember the two principles from
还记得之前说的两大原则吗
Every piece of data has a source
每一条数据都有一个数据源
of truth and when you access
当你访问那个数据时
that data, you create a
你在上面创建了一个依赖
So we've created our source of
我们已经创建了数据源
truth but we don't have a
但是我们还没有一个依赖
Fortunately, it's really easy to
幸运的是
create dependencies on your
在你的可绑定对象上创建依赖
bindable objects.
是非常简单的
I brought up this very basic
这里有一个非常基础的图解
You can see we have our view
可以看到我们的视图层级在右侧
hierarchy in blue on the right
是蓝色的
and we have our model in green
我们的模型在左侧
on the left.
是绿色的
Now, we can connect the two
现在我们连接二者
creating a dependency using the
用 ObjectBinding Property Wrapper
ObjectBinding property wrapper.
创建一个依赖
And as we do this, each view
我们这么做时
that has that property wrapper
每一个有那个 Property Wrapper 的视图
will depend on the model that we
都取决于我们之前写的模型
Just like with state, when you
就像用 State 一样
use the ObjectBinding property
当你用 ObjectBinding Property Wrapper
wrapper and add that to your
将它添加到视图中时
view, the framework recognizes
框架会识别出
that there's a dependency there.
那儿有一个依赖
And so in body, when you access
所以在主体中
that data, we automatically
当你访问那个数据时
figure out when to update your
我们自动明白什么时候刷新视图
In code, this looks something
在代码里看起来就像这样
When you create your view, you
你创建视图时
add the ObjectBinding property
添加 ObjectBinding Property Wrapper
wrapper to a property in your
到你视图里的一个 Property
And then when you instantiate
当你实例化视图时
your view, you just pass the
你只是将引用传递给
reference to your model that you
你已有的模型
Note that this creates an
注意 这在视图的实例中
explicit dependency in the
创建了一个
initializer of the view, which
清楚的依赖
is really great because now
这样很棒
anytime I go to instantiate my
因为每次我要实例化视图时
view, I know that it has a
我都知道模型上
dependency on the model.
有个依赖
And that's it.
就是这样
And as we do this, each view
我们这么做时
with the property wrapper will
每个有 Property Wrapper 的视图
automatically subscribe the
都会自动订阅
changes in our BindableObject,
BindableObject 的变化
which means we get automatic
也就意味着我们实现了
dependency tracking.
依赖自动追踪
Again, no manual invalidation or
又不需要
synchronization needed.
失效和同步了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So I want to pause and take
这里我想停一下
careful note here because if
有一点需要强调
using SwiftUI are value types,
因为如果用 SwiftUI
any time you're using a
是值类型的话
reference type, you should be
每次你使用引用类型时
using the ObjectBinding property
你都应该用 ObjectBinding Property Wrapper
This way the framework will know
这样当数据改变时
when that data changes and can
框架就会知道
keep your view hierarchy up to
然后让你的视图层级随之改变
So that's how to create a
这就是如何在 BindableObject 上
dependency using ObjectBinding
如何使用 ObjectBinding
on BindableObject.
创建一个依赖
But we actually have another
其实我们还有一个工具
tool for creating these
也可以创建
dependencies as well.
这些依赖
You can create indirect
我们可以创建间接依赖
So I brought back a similar
所以我带了一个
diagram to the one that you just
和刚才大家看到的图解
saw, but this time our view has
很相似的一个图解
gained some children.
但是这次我们的视图中多了些子类
Next, I want to bring in the
接下来 我想要引入 Environment
If you've watched the SwiftUI
如果你看了 SwiftUI Essentials 讲解
Essentials talk, you know that
你就知道
the environment is a really
Environment 是非常好的封装
great encapsulation for pushing
它可以推动数据
data down through your view
一路向下流过视图层级
And using the environment object
使用 Environment Object Modifier
modifier, we can actually write
我们可以真正地
our BindableObject into the
把 BindableObject 写入 Environment
environment.
现在 我们的模型在 Environment 里
We can create dependencies on
我们可以用
our model by using the
EnvironmentObject Property Wrapper
EnvironmentObject property
在模型上
wrapper.
创建依赖
Now, by using this property
现在 通过使用这个
wrapper, we can create a
Property Wrapper
dependency on that model.
我们可以在那个模型上创建依赖
But there's more.
但是不止这样
You can actually use this in
你可以在很多地方
multiple places.
用到它
So you can use this in a variety
所以你可以
of views throughout your
在整个层级的
hierarchy and they will all
各种视图中使用它
depend on the same model.
它们都依赖于同一个模型
And, of course, when that data
当然 数据变化
changes, everything will get
一切都会自动
updated automatically.
随之更新
You get the same automatic
你获得了
dependency tracking as you do
和 ObjectBinding 相同的
with ObjectBinding.
依赖追踪
You describe the dependency to
你用这些工具
SwiftUI by using these tools and
把依赖描述给 SwiftUI
the framework handles the rest.
框架会处理其他的部分
It's pretty great.
这很棒
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So let's update our podcast
这个便捷的方法
player to take advantage of
就可以更新我们的播客播放器
To do that, this is it.
就像这样
You just need to add the
你只需要添加
EnvironmentObject property
EnvironmentObject Property Wrapper 到视图
wrapper to the view and then in
然后在视图
an ancestor higher up in the
上方的父类中
hierarchy just provide the model
只用 EnvironmentObject Modifier
using the EnvironmentObject
提供模型
Now, whenever we use our player
现在 不论什么时候
in the body, SwiftUI will
只要我们在主体中使用播放器
automatically update our view on
SwiftUI 就会自动替我们更新数据
So you're probably wondering
你可能会想
when would I use
什么时候用
EnvironmentObject versus
EnvironmentObject
ObjectBinding?
什么时候用 ObjectBinding
Well, you can actually build
实际上你可以使用 ObjectBinding
your whole app with
构建整个 App
ObjectBinding, but it can get
但是从出栈到进栈
kind of cumbersome to pass
传递模型
around the model from hop to
会比较冗长
And that's where
这时候就需要
EnvironmentObject comes in.
EnvironmentObject 了
It's a really useful convenience
这真的很方便
for passing data around your
不直接在层级间
hierarchy indirectly.
传输数据
Here, you can see by using
这里 你可以看到
EnvironmentObject, we can pass
通过 EnvironmentObject
the model indirectly through our
我们可以间接传送模型
view hierarchy, which means we
通过视图层级
don't have to instantiate all
也就是说我们不需要
the intermediate views to the
用模型实例化所有的即时视图
hierarchy with the model.
到视图层级
So the environment is actually a
所以 Environment 真的是一个很好的方式
great way to pass all sorts of
用来间接传送各种数据
data indirectly down through
一路通过
your view hierarchy.
你的视图层级
And you might have seen its use
你可能已经看过
for things such as accent color
它在重点色
or layout direction and even
或布局方向等方面的应用
And as Luca said earlier, data
正如 Luca 刚才所说
comes in all sorts of shapes and
数据的形态结构多种多样
Well, values like accent color
值 像是重点色
and layout direction, those are
布局方向
just data.
它们只是数据
And when you use them in your
当你在视图中使用它们时
views, you're creating a
你就是在它们上面
dependency on them.
创建依赖
In fact, the environment is a
实际上 Environment 是一个
general purpose container for
通用集装箱
handling all sorts of indirect
可以用来处理各种
data and dependencies.
间接数据和依赖
And the framework uses it
框架自由使用它
liberally to give you rich
为你带来各种特色功能
features like Dynamic Type and
比如动态类型
Dark Mode.
和深色模式
You can also use the environment
你还可以
in previews to provide new
在预览中使用 Environment
values for things like the
给重点色或主题等
accent color or theme.
赋新值
So that's a quick tour through
我们已经快速过了一遍
the powerful tools we have in
SwiftUI 里
SwiftUI for handling data.
处理数据的强大工具
Next, I want to help you build
现在我让大家
some intuition for how to use
对如何使用正确的工具
the right tool and how they all
和如何调配它们
fit together.
有一个概念
One of the big themes here is
这里主题之一是
that every piece of data has a
每一条数据
single source of truth.
都有单一数据源
And in SwiftUI, we really have
在 SwiftUI 中
two options for managing these
我们有两种选择
sources of truth.
去处理这些数据源
First, we have state.
第一种是 State
State is great for data that's
State 适合本地视图的数据
view local, a value type,
一个值类型
managed, allocated and created
由框架
by the framework.
处理 分配 和创建
And BindableObject is great for
BindableObject 适合
data that you control.
你控制的数据
It's great for representing
它适用于给 SwiftUI 展现
external data to SwiftUI such as
外部数据
in onDevice database, this is
比如在 onDevice 数据库
storage that you manage, which
这里有你处理的内存
makes it great for the model
对你已有的模型
that you already have.
很有帮助
So now that we've talked about
现在我们已经了解了
sources of truth, I want to talk
数据源 接下来
a little bit about building
我想介绍一下
reusable components.
构建可重复使用的组件
One of the things that's great
SwiftUI 的一个优点是
about SwiftUI is that views are
视图是
low cost obstruction.
低成本阻塞
And what that means is that you
这意味着
don't have to make the tradeoff
我们不需要
between great architecture and
在架构和性能之间做折中
You can build the architecture
你可以搭建
you've always wanted to build
你想搭建的架构
and you can also get great
同时也能获得很好的性能
You don't have to make the
你不需要
straight off.
权衡折中
And with SwiftUI, you can focus
通过 SwiftUI 你可以集中精力于
on making your views into
让你的视图成为
reusable components.
可重复使用的组件
When you do this, you'll
当你这么做时
probably notice that most of the
你可能会注意到
time when you're using data in
在视图中使用数据时
your views, you probably don't
你也许不需要
need to mutate it.
改写它
And so, read-only access is
所以当你可以不管它时
preferred when you can get away
只读路径是更好的选择
For that, we have Swift
在这一点上 我们有 Swift Property
properties and the environment.
和 Environment
And because views in SwiftUI are
因为视图在 SwiftUI 中是
value types, the framework can
值类型
automatically determine when
框架可以自动确定
your data changes and update
数据什么时候改变
your view as a result.
视图也会随之变化
In general, you should prefer
总的来说 你应该倾向于选择
immutable access, but sometimes
不可改写访问
you do need to mutate a value.
但是有时你确实需要改写值
And for that, we have binding.
这时我们有 Binding
As Luca told you earlier, a
正如 Luca 刚才告诉大家的
binding is first class reference
Binding 是数据的第一类对象
It allows your components to
它可以让你的组件
read and write a value without
在不拥有的情况下
owning it.
读写数据
And this makes it great for
这对于可重复使用来说很有利
In fact, you can get a binding
实际上 你可以
to many different
绑定到很多不同的
representations of data.
数据表现
We showed you today how to get a
今天我们将展示如何
binding to state, but you can
绑定到 State
also get a binding to an
和如何绑定到
ObjectBinding.
ObjectBinding
In fact, you can get a binding
实际上 你也可以
to another binding as well.
绑定另一个绑定
All you need to do is use the
你只需要用
dollar sign prefix as we showed
我们之前展示的
you earlier.
美元符号前缀
It allows you to derive a
它可以让你
binding from another one of
从其他工具之一里
these tools.
生成一个绑定
I want to pause for a minute and
我想停一下让大家欣赏
appreciate how powerful this is.
这是多么有用
Earlier on, Luca showed you that
刚才 Luca 展示了
many of the components we vend
我们在 SwiftUI 里提供的组件
in SwiftUI, they operate on
它们运行在 Binding 上
So let's use Toggle for example.
接下来以 Toggle 为例
Toggle takes a binding to a
Toggle 把绑定给到 Boolean
But the beauty of data in
但是 SwiftUI 中数据的美观性在于
SwiftUI is that Toggle doesn't
Toggle 不需要知道
need to know or care where that
或不需要在意
Boolean lives or comes from.
Boolean 在哪儿或来自哪儿
All it needs to do is know how
它要做的只是
to read the value and change the
知道如何读取和改变值
Binding is a tool that
Binding 是一个工具
encapsulates these operations
它可以封装这些操作
which gets this separation of
而且同时
concern to the Toggle.
不需要考虑 Toggle
And this is the real power of
这是在 SwiftUI 中使用数据的
using data in SwiftUI.
真正魅力所在
You can get great correctness
你可以做到非常准确
and great separation of
而且不需要担心其他的
So you'll notice, I didn't
你会发现
actually mention state when I
在我讲解
was talking about building
搭建可重复使用组件的时候
reusable components.
我实际并没怎么提及 State
Well, state is trapped inside of
State 被卡在你的
your view and its children.
视图以及它的子类里
So if your component needs to
所以如果你的组件需要
operate on a value that's
操作一个值
external or somewhere else,
一个来自外部或其他地方的值
state might not be a great fit.
State 也许不合适
And state is a fantastic tool
对于原型开发第一步来说
for prototyping a first
State 是一个很好的工具
approach, as you saw today with
正如你今天看到的
our podcast player.
它在我们播客播放器上的表现一样
But most of the time, your data
但是大部分情况下
is going to live outside
你的数据是存在于
SwiftUI.
SwiftUI 之外的
For example, your data might
比如数据可能
live in a database and that will
在一个数据库里
probably be represented by
这可能就需要其他东西来展现它
something like a BindableObject.
比如 BindableObject
So if you find yourself reaching
所以如果你要用 State 的话
for state, please take a step
请退一步
back and consider, does this
考虑一下
data really need to be owned by
数据真的需要
this view?
被视图拥有吗
Perhaps the data, the state
也许数据 状态
should be lifted up into a
需要被提到父类
parent as Luca showed you
就像刚才 Loca 展示的那样
earlier or maybe that data can
或者数据可以
just be represented by an
被外部源
external source using a
通过 BindableObject 展现
So it's important to be careful
所以使用数据时
when using state, but it does
需要非常小心
have its strengths.
但它确实有它的优点
One of the great uses of state
State 的一大用途是
that we have in our framework is
我们框架里有按钮
Button uses state to track
按钮用 State 追踪
whether the user is pressing on
用户是否按下了按钮
it and highlight appropriately.
然后以合适的方式高亮它
And what's great about using
通过 State 处理按钮的好处是
state for button is that when
当你创建了一个按钮
you create a button, you don't
你不需要再考虑
need to care about the highlight
高亮状态
That is data that is truly owned
数据真正
by the button.
归按钮所有
So when you're reaching for
所以当你要用 State 时
state, consider do I have a case
你需要考虑的是
that's like button?
情况是否和按钮一样
And if you do, state might be a
如果一样的话
great tool.
State 或许是个很好的工具
But if not, consider using one
如果情况不一样
of the other powerful tools
那你就要考虑使用其他工具了
we've shown you for using data
我们刚才也为大家展示了
in SwiftUI.
这些 SwiftUI 中的工具
So that's how to build reusable
这就是如何用 SwiftUI
components with SwiftUI.
构建可重复使用组件
But what we've shown you here is
我们在这里向大家展示的是
actually generally applicable to
对所有类型的软件都适用的
all sorts of software.
普遍情况
Every piece of software has data
每个软件都有数据
and every piece of software has
而且每个软件都有
data access.
数据访问
And by carefully understanding
仔细了解你的数据
your data, minimizing your
尽量减少
sources of truth, and building
数据源
reusable components, you can
构建可重复使用组件
eliminate an entire class of
你可以消除一整级的 Bug
And when you use SwiftUI,
使用 SwiftUI 时
applying these concepts is
应用这些观念
incredibly easy because we've
会非常简单
built them right into the
因为我们已经把它们
framework.
应用在框架里了
We have a number of related
我们还有很多关于
sessions on SwiftUI and I
SwiftUI 的讲解
encourage you to check out all
我建议大家去看一下所有的相关介绍
It will change the way you build
这将会改变你搭建 App 的方式
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]